var questions = [
  {
    "question":
        "According to the table, which Treasury security has the highest yield?",
    "answers": [
      "3 Month",
      "2 Year",
      "10 Year",
      "30 Year",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0,
  },
  {
    "question":
        "What is the yield change in basis points for the 5-year Treasury over the last month?",
    "answers": [
      "+9 bps",
      "+14 bps",
      "+24 bps",
      "+27 bps",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3,
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Treasury security has a coupon rate of 4.88%?",
    "answers": [
      "2 Year",
      "5 Year",
      "10 Year",
      "30 Year",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0,
  },
  {
    "question":
        "If an investor buys \$10,000 worth of 10-year Treasury bonds at the current price listed, how many bonds can they purchase?",
    "answers": [
      "105.56 bonds",
      "104.84 bonds",
      "104.28 bonds",
      "103.58 bonds",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
  },
  {
    "question":
        "If the yield of the 2-year Treasury is projected to increase by 5 basis points from the current rate, what will be its new yield?",
    "answers": [
      "4.98%",
      "4.93%",
      "4.85%",
      "4.88%",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0,
  },
  {
    "question":
        "If the 30-year Treasury yield decreased by 0.10%, how much would the bond price change, assuming a direct relationship between yield and price? Assume a direct correlation between yield and price, with the price change being directly proportional to the yield change.",
    "answers": [
      "Decrease by approximately 2.3%",
      "Increase by approximately 2.3%",
      "Decrease by approximately 1.5%",
      "Increase by approximately 1.5%",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation":
        "A decrease in the yield generally causes the bond price to increase. For long-term bonds like the 30-year Treasury, even small changes in yield can lead to significant price changes.\nWith a yield decrease of 0.10%, the bond price is expected to increase by approximately 2.3% based on historical averages and the duration of a 30-year bond.",
  },
  {
    "question":
        "If the coupon rate of the 5-year Treasury increased by 0.5%, and the bond price remained the same, what would the new yield be?",
    "answers": [
      "4.10%",
      "4.55%",
      "5.10%",
      "4.73%",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2,
    "explanation":
        "Current Coupon Rate: 4.63%\nNew Coupon Rate: 4.63% + 0.5% = 5.13%\nWith the bond price unchanged, the yield will match the new coupon rate.",
  },
  {
    "question":
        "Assume that the prices of the 3-month and 6-month Treasury securities are expected to converge to an average value within the next month. What would this average price be?",
    "answers": [
      "5.24",
      "5.20",
      "5.22",
      "5.18",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1,
    "explanation":
        "3-month Treasury Price: 5.24\n6-month Treasury Price: 5.16\nAverage Price: (5.24+5.16) / 2 = 5.20",
  },
  {
    "question":
        "If an investor holds \$50,000 in 12-month Treasuries and reinvests the proceeds into 2-year Treasuries after one year, what will be the total interest earned if the yields remain unchanged?",
    "answers": [
      "\$5,055",
      "\$5,980",
      "\$4,935",
      "\$6,280",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0,
    "explanation":
        "12-month Treasury Yield: 5.18%\n2-year Treasury Yield: 4.93%\nInterest for the first year: 50000 Ã— 0.0518 = 2590\nInterest for the second year (based on the 2-year Treasury yield): 50000 x 0.0493 = 2465\nTotal Interest: 2590+2465 = 5055",
  },
  {
    "question":
        "Assuming an investor holds a portfolio of \$100,000 equally distributed among the 2-year, 5-year, and 10-year Treasuries, calculate the average yield of the portfolio.",
    "answers": [
      "4.71%",
      "4.61%",
      "4.94%",
      "5.18%",
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0,
  },
];
